Dr. Chanda Thapliyal Nautiyal

Assistant Professor (Mathematics)

7533935935 Uttarakhand chanda.nautiyal@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/chanda-nautiyal-141a78100/ Holds a Master's degree in Mathematics from DBS (PG) College and a Doctorate from Uttarakhand Technical University, specializing in 'Mathematical Modeling and Simulation of Digital Image Processing Problems.' Currently serving as an Assistant Professor at Government Degree College Narendra Nagar, Uttarakhand since 2015. With over six research papers published in reputed journals, conference proceedings, and book chapters, also authored a book on 'Numerical Analysis' for B.Sc. 3rd year and holds a patent.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Conferred upon the "Young Scientist Award -2010" for best paper presentation by Uttarakhand Council of Science and Technology (UCOST), Dehradun.

Secured the first rank at University level during M.Sc.

Sensor assembly for evaluating fluid dynamic for a mechanical system and method thereof" (published in Indian Patent Journal as 9th author on 31/12/21)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Professor		Department of Higher Education , Uttarakhand		Jan 2015 - Present
•				
Project Scientist		Uttarakhand Council for Science and technology (UCOST), Dehrad	lun	Oct 2013 - Jan 2015
Assistant. Professor-Contractual		SGRR (P.G.) College, Dehradun		Sep 2011 - Sep 2013
Assistant. Professor-Contractual		P.L.M.S. Govt. P.G. College, Rishikesh		Nov 2008 - Jun 2010
Lecturer, Mathematics		Graphic Era University, Dehradu	ın	Jul 2007 - Aug 2008
EDUCATION				
Ph. D: Mathematical Modeling and Simulation of Image Processing Problems	Uttarakhand Technical University			Jul 2013 - Dec 2018
M. Sc: Mathematics	DBS (P.G.	.) College, Dehradun	78%	Jul 2001 - Jun 2003
B. Sc: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry	DBS (P.G.	.) College, Dehradun	71.8%	Jul 1998 - Jul 2001

PUBLICATIONS

(Published Papers)

1. Nautiyal, C. T. (2022). Optimum economic ordering and preservation technology expenditure strategy facing non-instantaneous degrading inventory as a consequence of composite impact of advertisement, trade-credit besides inflation. *International Journal of Mathematical Modelling and Numerical Optimisation*, 12(2), 113-140.(DOI 10.1504/IJMMNO.2022.10043097)

- 2. Published research paper titled "SETTING UP AN EOQ MODEL WITH SALVAGE VALUE WHERE THE COST OF HOLDING AND THE DEMAND RATE ARE NONLINEAR TIME FUNCTIONS" in 3rd International Conference on "Advances in Engineering, Sciences And Technology"
- 3. Nautiyal, C. T., Singh, S., & Rana, U. S. (2020). Pattern Classification Using ART 1 Network. *PalArch's Journal of Archaeology of Egypt/Egyptology*, 17(9), 8038-8044.(https://archives.palarch.nl/index.php/jae/article/view/5706)
- 4. **Nautiyal,** C. T., Singh, S., & Rana, U. S. (2018). Recognition of noisy numbers using neural network, 'Soft Computing: Theories and Applications' (pp.23-132). Springer, Singapore. (DOI: https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-10-5699-4_13)
- 5. **Nautiyal,** C.T., Singh, S. and Rana, U.S. (2017), Noisy Character Recognition, 'Global Journal of Pure and Applied Mathematics', 13(6), 1875-1892.(ISSN: **0973-1768**)
- 6. **Nautiyal,** C.T., Singh, S., Rana, U.S. and Kumar, R. (2016), October, Classification of noisy English alphabets using neural network, in 'Next Generation Computing Technologies (NGCT), 2016 2nd International Conference on', 704-709. IEEE.
- 7. **Chanda,** Singh Sunita, Rana U.S. (2016). Evaluation of Huffman code and B-code Algorithms for Image Compression Standards. *Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing (Springer Publication*), 436: 1051-1060.
- 8. **Thapliyal Chanda,** Singh Sunita (2014). Image Restoration Techniques in Perspective of Safeguard Window. *International Journal of Advanced Technology & Engineering Research* (IJATER) (IOCRSEM- 2014), 220-223.
- 9. **Nautiyal Thapliyal Chanda**, Singh Sunita and Rana U S (2013). Evaluation of Huffman-code, B-code and Shift- code Algorithms for Image Compression Standards, abstract paper of 8th *Uttarakhand State Science and technology Congress-2013, Doon University, Dehradun.*
- 10. Nautiyal Thapliyal Chanda and Singh Sunita (2012). Visual Servo Control Design for The tracking of Objects, abstract paper of 7th Uttarakhand State Science and technology Congress-2012, Graphic Era University, Dehradun.
- 11. **Thapliyal Chanda** and Sunita (2010). Visual Servo Control Design of Robotic Manipulator Object Using Neural Network, abstract paper of 5th *Uttarakhand State Science and technology Congress-2010, Doon University, Dehradun.*

(Accepted Papers)

1. Impact of inflation and discount on optimum ordering and preservation technology expenses scheme of perishable inventory model (Int. J. of Mathematics in Operational Research, Inderscience Publishers)

SEMINARS/WORKSHOPS PARTICIPATED

- 28th Feb 2016 organized by Centre for Information Technology University of Petroleum and Energy Studies Dehradun in association with Next Generation Computing Technologies Society.
- Attended "Orientation Workshop on Policy Making and Environmental Statistics for Sustainable Development" during 16-17th Oct 2015 at Doon University, Dehradun.
- Presented paper in "NAAC sponsored National Seminar on Role of IQAC in Enhancing Quality of Teaching, Learning and Evaluation Process" during 09-10th Oct 2015 at SGRR (PG) College, Dehradun.
- Attended "Sensitization Workshop on PCPNDT Act & Save the Girl Child" on 3rd March 2015 at Doon University, Dehradun.
- Participated in "World Conference on Advances in Communication and Control System-CACCS-2013" during 6-8th April 2013 at DIT University Dehradun.
- Participated in "Study Group Meeting on Industrial Problems" held at IIT Roorkee from 16-03-2009 to 21-03-2009.

OTHER ACTIVITIES:

- Completed "Refresher Course in Applicable Mathematics" from 15-29, December 2021 organized by the Teaching Learning Centre, Ramanujan College, University of Delhi in collaboration with the Deshbandhu College, University of Delhi.
- Completed "Orientation Program" from 23rd July to 17th August 2018 at Academic Staff College, Jawaharlal Nehru University, New Delhi.
- Completed "Refresher Course" from 31st May 2019 to 14th June 2019 at University of Delhi, Delhi.
- Completed "short term training program" (Training of Teachers for Teachers under TLC project) from 25/11/2019 to 29/11/2019 at SGRR(P.G.) College, Dehradun.
- Conducted National e-Workshop on "Technical Documentation using LaTeX" on 11/08/2021.
- Delivered Talk on "Application of Mathematical Models" at WHRC-NIH, Jammu during 28-29/12/2017.
- Coordinated the Technical session on "Chemistry" in 12th USSTC during 07-03-18 to 09-03-18 at Vigyan Dham, Jhajra, Dehradun.
- Coordinated the Technical session on "Science & Society/ Science Communication and Innovator" in 11th USSTC during 02-03-17 to 04-03-17 at Vigyan Dham, Jhajra, Dehradun.
- Coordinated the Technical session on "Biotechnology, Biochemistry and Microbiology" in 10th USSTC during 10-02-16 to 12-02-16 at Vigyan Dham, Jhajra, Dehradun.
- Coordinated the Technical session on "Botany" in 9th USSTC during 26-02-15 to 28-02-15 at Vigyan Dham, Jhajra, Dehradun.
- Part of Coordination Committee for organizing two days' workshop on "Scientific Paper Writing And Technological Empowerment of Women" 17th & 18th June 2014 at Graphic Era University Dehradun organized by UCOST & NASI,

Uttarakhand Chapter.

- Part of Coordination Committee for organizing workshop on "Harnessing Intellectual Property & Its Management for Growth and Prosperity" held on 17th May 2014 at Gurukul Kangri Vishwavidyalaya, Haridwar.
- Delivered lecture on Intellectual Property Right (IPR) in workshop organized by Govt. P.G. College, Dakpathar Dehradun on 7th Nov. 2013.
- Co-coordinated the Brain storming session on "Occupational and nutritional health hazards" in 8th USSTC during 26-12-13 to 28-12-13 held at Doon University Dehradun.
- Coordinated the Technical session on "Environmental Science and Forestry" in 8th USSTC during 26-12-13 to 28-12-13 at Doon University Dehradun.
- Completed "Orientation Program" from 23rd July to 17th August 2018 at Academic Staff College, Jawaharlal Nehru University, New Delhi.
- Completed "Refresher Course" from 31st May 2019 to 14th June 2019 at University of Delhi, Delhi.
- Completed **"short term training program"** (Trainig of Teachers for Teachers under TLC project) from 25/11/2019 to 29/11/2019 at SGRR(P.G.) College, Dehradun